Finding Aid for the James L. Britton III Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
James L. Britton III Collection
1836-1875
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0053
.21 linear_feet
Biography/History
Mr. and Mrs. James L. Britton III were natives of Nashville, Tennessee, with Mrs. Britton being a 1958 graduate of Vanderbilt University.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains 13 rare Nineteenth Century imprints relating to the State of Tennessee. The .21 linear feet of material will be housed in 13 file folders and stored in a manuscript box.
- Acts and Resolutions (1)
  - State of Tennessee
  - 34th General Assembly, Extra Session, July 1866.
- Annual Report (1)
  - Sunday-School Society of the
  - Methodist Episcopal Church, South, 1860
- Book (1)
  - Parson Brownlow and the Unionists of East Tennessee, 1862
- Broadsides (4)
  - Rules for taking Depositions, State of Tennessee, March 18, 1853. (Folder 1)
  - General Orders No. 18, Private Resolution-No. 7. Joint Resolution authorizing the Secretary of War to audit and pay the claim of Robert T. Kirkpatrick, a loyal citizen of Tennessee, for materials taken and used in building a fort for Nashville, March 6, 1871. (Folder 2)
  - General Orders No. 20, Resolution-No.13. Authorizing the sale of the Chattanooga rolling-mill property, at Chattanooga, Tennessee, to the Southwestern Iron Company. March 6, 1871. (Folder 3)
  - General Orders No. 50, Public Resolution-No.30. A Resolution directing the Secretary of War to furnish certain arms and equipment to the State of Tennessee. April 9, 1867. (Folder 4)
- Governor’s Message (1)
  - Message of James D. Porter
  - 39th General Assembly of the State of Tennessee, Nashville, 1875
- Proceedings (1)
  - Unconditional Union Convention, of West Tennessee
  - Convened in Memphis, February 22, 1864
  - To Inaugurate the Movement for the Reorganization of the State
- Reports (2)
  - Tennessee Mounted Volunteers, The Committee of Claims, to whom was referred the petition of twenty-two volunteers, of the State of Tennessee, for per diem pay and forage for horses. May 16, 1848. (Folder 1)
  - Tennessee River, Letter from the Secretary of War, transmitting information required by a resolution in relation to the progress and condition of the improvement of the Tennessee River. April 20, 1836. (Folder 2)
- Sheet Music (2)
  - The Chattanooga, The Committee of Claims, to whom was referred the petition of twenty-two volunteers, of the State of Tennessee, for per diem pay and forage for horses. May 16, 1848. (Folder 1)
  - Tennessee River, Letter from the Secretary of War, transmitting information required by a resolution in relation to the progress and condition of the improvement of the Tennessee River. April 20, 1836. (Folder 2)
- Sheet Music (2)
  - The Chattanooga (Folder 1)
    Grand March
    Dedicated to Major General George M. Thomas
    Composed by E. Mack, Philadelphia, 1864
  - Carry Me Back To Tennessee or Ellie Rhee (Folder 2)
    Written and arranged by Sep. Winner, Philadelphia, 1865